<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[BlindFolded Archer]]></title>
  <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-10-26T15:51:27+01:00</updated>
  <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Don]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Second System Effect - Thunderbird Woes]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/11/09/the-second-system-effect-thunderbird-woes/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-09T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/11/09/the-second-system-effect-thunderbird-woes</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My anecdotal evidence - Since 2005, there have been issues with Thunderbird speaking to IMAP servers, specifically saving messages to the sent folder. I assume there have been a bug filed for this but we are now in 2011 and this issue still exists in Thunderbird 7 - So much for progress.</p>

<p><a title="Thunderbird Issue" href="http://forums.mozillazine.org/viewtopic.php?t=218625&amp;start=0." target="_blank">Issue Discussion Here:</a></p>

<p>I really hate it when people point me to forums, as a source of a solution - especially ones that are 12 pages long! If you do not want to help, then don&#8217;t reply! You do have a choice.</p>

<p>Anyway this reminds me of the highly charged jwz, who says it much better than me - even gave it a cool name -  <a title="CADT" href="http://www.jwz.org/doc/cadt.html">CADT</a>.</p>

<p>Note that he was referring to Gnome 1 -&gt; 2, and now we have the monstrosity that is Gnome 3! So much for progress!</p>

<p>To al who says Google is your friend - the account settings are no longer under &#8216;Tools&#8217;
they are now under &#8216;Edit&#8217;.</p>

<p>Basically there are 2 things to do -</p>

<ul>
    <li>Reduce server connections cache to 1.</li>
</ul>


<ul>
    <li>In &#8216;copies and folders&#8217; under &#8216;Account Settings&#8217;, uncheck the box to automatically place copies in &#8216;local&#8217; folders, rather have them stored in the server. The way IMAP works, you will still get these in your folders - go figure. Until they fix this issue, we will still have this problem!</li>
</ul>


<p>Only link I found that gave me an idea on the folder thingy was by <a title="Dr Nabeel" href="http://nabtron.com/thunderbird-stuck-on-copying-message-to-sent-folder-solved-on-mac-osx/2909/" target="_blank">Dr Nabeel</a></p>

<p>The reason for this post title? <a title="second system effect" href="The second-system effect refers to the tendency of small, elegant, and successful systems to have elephantine, feature-laden monstrosities as their successors. ">Wikipedia</a> is your friend!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Do Not Equate To Skill, What Can Easily Be Attributed To Luck]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/11/07/do-not-equate-to-skill-what-can-easily-be-attributed-to-luck/"/>
    <updated>2011-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/11/07/do-not-equate-to-skill-what-can-easily-be-attributed-to-luck</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A post on a post about a post. How many layers of abstraction? Reminds me of paper money!</p>

<p>Do not really like linking to other posts - but this hits the nail on the head. The so called masters of the universe have no idea luck and serendipity plays such an important role in their &#8216;achievements&#8217;. Much better analysis than can be done by me.</p>

<p>Excellent post by Fred Dustin on Hubris - [http://www.freddestin.com/blog/2011/11/ows-2-hubris-in-the-face-of-risk-and-a-culture-of-entitlement.html].</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[RIP Dennis..]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/10/13/rip-dennis/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/10/13/rip-dennis</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>A great <a title="Dennis" href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dennis_Ritchie" target="_blank">man</a> passed today. Unassuming and truly a legend, at least in my eyes.</p>

<p>If you haven&#8217;t read it - go buy it now! Once you can program in C - you can do anything.</p>

<p><a title="Ansi C" href="http://www.amazon.com/Programming-Language-2nd-Brian-Kernighan/dp/0131103628">The C Programming Language.</a></p>

<p>&nbsp;</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How to BackUp]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/09/15/how-to-backup/"/>
    <updated>2011-09-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/09/15/how-to-backup</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Don&#8217;t break what works - this constant to re-invent the wheel! sheesh</p>

<p>is Emacs broken, is Gnutils?</p>

<p>After reading the very unhelpful advice on <a title="Ubuntu backup" href="https://help.ubuntu.com/community/BackupYourSystem">Ubuntu</a> on how to backup - I have stolen the old notes from jwz.</p>

<p>http://www.jwz.org/doc/backups.html</p>

<ul>
    <li>You have a computer. It came with a hard drive in it. Go buy two more drives of the same size or larger. If the drive in your computer is SATA2, get SATA2. If it&#8217;s a 2.5&#8221; laptop drive, get two of those. Brand doesn&#8217;t matter, but physical measurements and connectors should match.</li>
    <li>Get external enclosures for both of them. The enclosures are under $30.</li>
    <li>Put one of these drives in its enclosure on your desk. Name it something clever like &#8220;Backup&#8221;. If you are using a Mac, the command you use to back up is this:
<pre><strong>sudo rsync -vaxAX --delete --ignore-errors / /Volumes/Backup/</strong></pre>
If you&#8217;re using Linux, it&#8217;s something a lot like that. If you&#8217;re using Windows, go fuck yourself.</li>
    <li>If you have a desktop computer, have this happen every morning at 5AM by creating a temporary text file containing this line:
<pre><strong>0 5 * * * rsync -vaxAX --delete --ignore-errors / /Volumes/Backup/</strong></pre>
and then doing <strong><tt>sudo crontab -u root <em>that-file</em></tt></strong>

If you have a laptop, do that before you go to bed. Really. Every night when you plug your laptop in to charge.</li>
    <li>If you&#8217;re on a Mac, that backup drive will be <em>bootable.</em> That means that when (WHEN) your internal drive scorches itself, you can just take your backup drive and put it in your computer and go. This is nice.</li>
    <li>When (WHEN) your backup drive goes bad, which you will notice because your last backup failed, replace it immediately. This is your number one priority. Don&#8217;t wait until the weekend when you have time, do it now, before you so much as <em>touch</em> your computer again. Do it before goddamned breakfast. The universe tends toward maximum irony. Don&#8217;t push it.</li>
    <li>That third drive? Do a backup onto it the same way, then take that to your office and lock it in a desk. Every few months, bring it home, do a backup, and immediately take it away again. This is your &#8220;my house burned down&#8221; backup.</li>
</ul>


<p><em>&#8220;OMG, three drives is so expensive! That sounds like a hassle!&#8221;</em> Shut up. I know things. You will listen to me. Do it anyway.</p>

<p>Excellent advice!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Unix Help For Users]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/07/03/unix-help-for-users/"/>
    <updated>2011-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/07/03/unix-help-for-users</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://unixhelp.ed.ac.uk/">http://unixhelp.ed.ac.uk/</a>
Nuff Said.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[How Not to Hack the Android Framework]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/06/22/Hacking-Android-FrameWork/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-22T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/06/22/Hacking-Android-FrameWork</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="meta">22 June 2011 - Amsterdam</p>


<p>This is a short dump of my notes to a customer who hacked the Android framework to create a custom build for their project. The resulting system was unstable and my job was to find out why (and fix it).</p>

<blockquote><p>Comparing a stock android emulator (both 2.2 and 2.3), we see comparable values for highly graphic intensive apps.</p>

<p>The difference in system-server could be down to our additions and the amount of processes - for each process needs to
communicate it&#8217;s state and activities to system_server (package manager, activity manager etc, ContentProvider resolver), the more the process, the more
the messages as the framework need to know which activities, services, providers and broadcast is running.</p>

<p>I have instrumented the framework and could not find any extra  messages due to increased CotentProvider usages or broadcast recievers, although I can now track the message to the actual package/classs
the quantity/frequencty was sufficiently low.</p>

<p>system_server crashes because it has run out of FD(file descriptors!).</p></blockquote>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Chronos and BeagleBoard/Pandaboard]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/06/01/Chronos-BeagleBoard/"/>
    <updated>2011-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/06/01/Chronos-BeagleBoard</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p class="meta">1 June 2011 - London</p>


<p>Check out this awesome watch <a href="http://processors.wiki.ti.com/index.php/EZ430-Chronos">Chronos</a></p>

<p>Looking forward to playing with it as I just ordered it.</p>

<p>Stay tuned for more information once it arrives!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[LLVM - What is it?]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/03/07/llvm-compiler-infrastructure/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/03/07/llvm-compiler-infrastructure</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>What is LLVM? It&#8217;s homepage is somewhat cryptic - spends the first paragraph telling people what it is NOT!</p>

<p><a title="LLVM" href="http://www.llvm.org/">llvm</a></p>

<p>In POE - it is used to build compilers - that means you can invent your own language, and use LLVM build the compiler and intepreter for you - voila!</p>

<p>The abstract from the original paper by Chris is more enlightening:</p>

<pre>This paper describes LLVM (Low Level Virtual Machine),
a compiler framework designed to support transparent,
lifelong program analysis and transformation for arbitrary programs,
by providing high-level information to compiler
transformations at compile-time, link-time, run-time, and in
idle time between runs. LLVM deﬁnes a common, low-level
code representation in Static Single Assignment (SSA) form,
with several novel features: a simple, language-independent
type-system that exposes the primitives commonly used to
implement high-level language features; an instruction for
typed address arithmetic; and a simple mechanism that can
be used to implement the exception handling features of
high-level languages (and setjmp/longjmp in C) uniformly
and eﬃciently. The LLVM compiler framework and code
representation together provide a combination of key capabilities
that are important for practical, lifelong analysis and
transformation of programs. To our knowledge, no existing
compilation approach provides all these capabilities. We describe
the design of the LLVM representation and compiler
framework, and evaluate the design in three ways: (a) the
size and eﬀectiveness of the representation, including the
type information it provides; (b) compiler performance for
several interprocedural problems; and (c) illustrative examples of the
beneﬁts LLVM provides for several challenging
compiler problems.</pre>


<p>&#8230;er. Ok for those who are still wondering what it is - check out Chris&#8217; presentation at <a title="llvm fosdem" href="http://llvm.org/pubs/2011-02-FOSDEM-LLVMAndClang.html">FOSDEM</a> - (did I tell you I also presented at <a title="The McDonalds Model" href="http://blindfoldedarcher.com/the-mcdonalds-model/">FOSDEM</a> this year - my claim to fame! )</p>

<p>Even Google is using LLVM in Android - check out <a title="RenderScript" href="http://developer.android.com/guide/topics/renderscript/index.html" target="_blank">RenderScript</a> (beautiful stuff!!).</p>

<p>I still love GCC, but I will not ignore it&#8217;s shortcomings. As an engineer, we should strive to understand our tools especially it&#8217;s limitation</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The McDonalds Model]]></title>
    <link href="http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/02/01/the-mcdonalds-model/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-01T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://teopeurt.github.com/blog/2011/02/01/the-mcdonalds-model</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>My talk at this year&#8217;s FOSDEM. Explaining the soon-to-be world changing Village Telco Mesh Potato!</p>

<div id="__ss_6830334" style="width: 425px;">

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

&nbsp;

<strong style="display: block; margin: 12px 0 4px;"><a title="VillageTelco FOSDEM WirelessDialog" href="http://www.slideshare.net/teopeurt/villagetelcofinal">VillageTelco FOSDEM WirelessDialog</a></strong>
<div style="padding: 5px 0 12px;">View more <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/">presentations</a> from <a href="http://www.slideshare.net/teopeurt">teopeurt</a></div>
&nbsp;

</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
